Malcolm S. Knowles Papers
Malcolm S. Knowles Papers
- Meetings files
  - Kentucky Educational Television, 1972-1973; general education development project (Box 20)
  - Kentucky Educational Television (cont., 1972-1973; general education development project (Box 21)
  - Learning community programme for staff development & training officers in Africa, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Liberal Religious Education Directors Association, 1965; annual fall conference (Box 21)
  - Massachusetts Board of Higher Education Advisory Council on Continuing Education, Massachusetts adult education planning conference, 1968 (Box 21)
  - Massachusetts Department of Correction, Mental Health, and Public Health, Governor's conference on nursing utilization, 1967 (Box 21)
  - Merrimack Education Center, 1970; local school planning (Box 21)
  - Montana adult education conference, 1971 (Box 21)
  - Mead Johnson, Nutritional Division, Educational process in neonatal care, 1980-1981 (Box 21)
  - National Academy for Health Inservice Education
    - Board of Directors, 1971 (Box 21)
    - Executive Committee, 1970 (Box 21)
  - National Association of Professors of Continuing and Adult Education (NAPCAE) / Adult Education Association of the U.S.A. (AEA/USA) joint conference, 1971 (Box 21)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ, 1966; consultation on the place of evaluation in program development (Box 21)
  - National Council on the Aging, Inc., Symposium and Advisory Board, 1981 (Box 21)
  - National Defense University Board of Visitors, 1979-1981 (Box 21)
  - National Health Care Management Center, Wharton School, National conference on management development in health care, 1980 (Box 21)
  - National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) Division of Manpower and Training Programs
    - Ad Hoc Advisory Committee, 1969 (Box 21)
    - Continuing Education Training Review Committee, 1972 (Box 21)
    - 11th Annual conference, 1972 (Box 21)
  - National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH), North Carolina Department of Mental Health 4th annual, 1968 (Box 21)
  - National League for Nursing, National Student Nurses Association convention, 1971 (Box 21)
  - National Seminar on Adult Education Research, 1966; 1968,; 1969; 3 folders (Box 22)
  - National University Extension Association (NUEA) Region III meeting, 1971 (Box 22)
  - New England Hospital Assembly, 45th annual conference, 1966 (Box 22)
  - New England Reading Association, 21st annual conference, 1969 (Box 22)
  - New York Association for Continuing Education (NYACE) / Association for Adult Education of New Jersey joint conference, 1974 (Box 22)
  - New York State Education Department, Office of Doctoral Projects Rating Committee, 1980 (Box 22)
  - North American Conference on Adult Education (NACAE), 1st annual conference, 1967 (Box 22)
  - North Carolina Adult Education Association annual conference, 1974 (Box 22)
  - North Carolina State University, Professional Growth and Development Committee, 1974 (Box 22)
  - Northeastern University, University College Adult education conference, 1970 (Box 22)
  - Ontario Camping Association, 1968 (Box 22)
  - Ontario Institute for Studies in Education
    - Department of Adult Education, Nature of the DHR specialization, 1971 (Box 22)
    - Department of Curriculum Development staff conference, 1970 (Box 22)
  - Phi Delta Kappa Commission on Lifelong Learning, 1974-1975; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Personnel and Management Services, Committee on Professional Education, 1969 (Box 22)
  - Polaroid Corporation, Management Development Committee, 1969 (Box 22)
  - Professional Development and Growth Committee, 1974 (Box 22)
  - ROCOM Division of Hoffmann-LaRoche, Inc., Advisory Panel on Multimedia Instructional System, 1970-1975; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Rutgers University
    - Center of Alcohol Studies, Subcommittee on Teaching and Training, 1973-1974 (Box 22)
    - Evening Extension Division Biennial Retreat, 1973 (Box 23)
  - Service-Learning Resource Center, North Carolina assembly on service learning, 1977 (Box 23)
  - Southeastern Library Association 26th Biennial conference, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Southern Regional Education Board Adult Basic Education Staff Development Project, Southeastern Region, 1971; planning for in-service workshops (Box 23)
  - State University of New York (SUNY)
    - Division of Continuing Education 50th Anniversary conference, 1973 (Box 23)
    - Evening and Extension Division 4th Annual conference, 1967 (Box 23)
  - Systems Management Corporation, Conference for the National Advisory Committee for the project to develop a preliminary manual of terminology about adult/continuing education, 1970-1971 (Box 23)
  - Undergraduate Teaching Improvement Council Conference on the changing student population, 1981 (Box 23)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO)
    - Institute for Education, 1972; lifelong learning consultation (Box 23)
    - International symposium on ways and means of strengthening information and counseling services for adult learners, 1977 (Box 23)
    - 3rd International conference on adult education, 1972 (Box 23)
    - Youth day for human rights, 1982 (Box 23)
  - United States Department of Agriculture / University of Georgia College of Agriculture, Conference for new extension personnel, 1975 (Box 23)
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW)
    - Professors of adult education research conference, 1964 (Box 23)
    - White House conference on aging, 1961 (Box 23)
  - University of Connecticut School of Education, State conference for adult educators, 1970 (Box 23)
  - University of Delaware Division of Continuing Education, Ad Hoc Committee on Adult/Continuing Education, 1974 (Box 23)
  - University of Maryland, Conferences and Institutes Division, Statewide conference on the future of community services/continuing education in Maryland higher educational institutions, 1974 (Box 23)
  - University of Pennsylvania National Health Care Center, National conference on management development in health care, 1980 (Box 24)
  - University of Rhode Island, 1969; evaluation of New England project on education for the aging (Box 24)
  - University of Texas Texas Educational Media Program / Texas Education Agency, KLRN-TV, Catalyst for adult learning symposium, 1972 (Box 24)
  - University of the West Indies Department of Extra-Mural Studies, Caribbean conference on agricultural extension, 1966 (Box 24)
  - Veterans Administration (VA), 31st Interagency institute and the 38th Hospital institute for federal hospital administrators, 1968 (Box 24)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University School of Nursing, National conference on continuing education for nurses, 1969 (Box 24)
  - Virginia Council of Churches, Conference on the future of church education, 1974 (Box 24)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute Donaldson Brown Center for Continuing Education, Successful continuing programs, 1980 (Box 24)
  - Vocational, technical and adult education, annual conference, 1973 (Box 24)
  - Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education, 11th annual training institute for psychiatrist-teachers of practicing physicians, 1971 (Box 24)
  - Wichita State University Action Training Service, Continuing education conference for ATS consultants and associated personnel, 1974 (Box 24)
  - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA)
    - Organization Development Project, 1962; planning committee and staff meetings; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Providence Central annual conference, 1969 (Box 24)
    - Training Institute on Interracial Advance conference, 1964 (Box 24)
    - Young Women's Christian Association Joint planning conference, 1970 (Box 24)
  - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) of Canada
    - National Council
      - 11th H-Y assembly, 1964 (Box 24)
      - Staff conference, 1968 (Box 24)
      - Staff meeting, 1967 (Box 24)
  - Young Presidents' Organization, 18th International university for presidents, 1968 (Box 24)
- Photographs
  - Commission of Professors of Adult Education (CPAE), circa late 1950's (Box 25)
  - Reception in honor of Malcolm S. and Hulda Knowles, and his 1974 graduates (Box 25)
- Printed material
  - Adult and continuing education research project, by Arthur L. Johnson, 1973 (Box 25)
  - Adult contemporary instructional guide, 1976 (Box 25)
  - Adult education and the school, by J.R. Kidd, 1952 (Box 25)
  - Adult Education Association of the U.S.A. (AEA/USA)
    - Adult education newsletter, vol. 1, no. 1, 1951 (Box 25)
    - AEA/USA reporter, Issue 1, 1977 (Box 25)
    - Proposal to the W.K. Kellogg Foundation, 1981 (Box 25)
    - Student-professor get acquainted evaluation results, 1966 (Box 25)
    - Working paper for a long-run plan of development, 1953 (Box 25)
  - Adult Education Association of Virginia
    - AEAV news, no. 2, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Adult education: current trends and practices, 1949 (Box 25)
  - Adult education for the 1970's: promise or illusion, by Jack London, circa 1973 (Box 25)
  - Adult education in France, by Colin J. Titmus, circa 1968 (Box 25)
  - Adult education in Germany: bibliography, by Armin L. Schadt, undated (Box 25)
  - Adult education in public school systems 1968-69 and 1969-70, by Imogene E. Okes, 1974 (Box 25)
  - Adult education in the modern university, by Special Committee of the National University Extension Association, 1949 (Box 25)
  - Adult education services of the state departments of education, by John B. Holden, 1959 (Box 25)
  - Adult education staff development: selected issues, alternatives and implications, ed. by George E. Spear, 1976 (Box 25)
  - Adult education: state demographic data, by National Advisory Council on Adult Education, 1973 (Box 25)
  - Adult leadership: study of subscribers and their reactions to the magazine, 1953 (Box 25)
  - Adult learner and ERIC: new vistas for research, by John A. Niemi and Daniel C. Jessen, undated (Box 25)
  - Adult learning activities: handbook of terminology for classifying and describing the learning activities of adults (draft 6), 1978 (Box 25)
  - Adult learning in America: examining Eduard Lindeman's agenda for lifelong education (proposed title and draft), by David W. Stewart, 1985 (Box 26)
  - Adult learning: issues and innovations, ed. by Robert M. Smith, 1976 (Box 26)
  - Adult learning projects: study of adult learning in urban and rural Tennessee, by John M. Peters and R. Susan Gordon, 1974 (Box 26)
  - Adult performance level research and curriculum design, by Sam V. Dauzat, undated (Box 26)
  - Adult program section of Associations of Secretaries, YMCA's of North America, Adult program digest, vol. 18, no. 1, 1955 (Box 26)
  - Adult and continuing education today (ACET), vol. 8, no. 23, 1978 (Box 26)
  - Advertisements, undated (Box 26)
  - Aerospace Corporation Orbiter, vol. 15, 1975 (Box 26)
  - Agenda of research on lifelong learning during adulthood from future directions for a learning society, 1978 (Box 26)
  - Alternatives for staff development of adult educators, by Florida adult educators, undated (Box 26)
  - American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education
    - Doctorate in education, vol. 2: Institutions, by Harold E. Moore, John H. Russel and Donald G. Ferguson, 1960 (Box 26)
  - American Association of Fund-Raising Counsel
    - Bulletin, vol. 7, quarterly, 1961 (Box 26)
  - American Association of Junior Colleges
    - Community services forum, v.2, no. 4, 1970 (Box 26)
  - American Library Association
    - ALA bulletin, 1954 (Box 26)
    - Library Community Projects manuscripts, 1956; 1957,; 1959 (Box 26)
  - American Society for Training and Development
    - Professional Development Committee, 1975-1978; papers and reports; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Study of professional training and development roles and competencies, by Patrick R. Pinto, Ph.D. and James W. Walker, Ph.D., 1978 (Box 27)
    - Triangle trainer, vol. 9, no. 10, 1981 (Box 27)
  - Americans volunteer, 1969 (Box 27)
  - Analysis of MAT scores vs. performance for adult and higher ed graduates (Ed.D.), undated (Box 27)
  - Andragogy: a new science, by Ger van Enckevort, circa 1971 (Box 27)
  - Annual handbook for group facilitators, selections, 1974 (Box 27)
  - Aontas review, vol. 1, no. 1, 1979 (Box 27)
  - Archdiocese of Chicago Center for Adult Learning, vol. 3, no. 4, 1974 (Box 27)
  - Architecture and adult education pamphlets and articles
  - Articles by Knowles, 1929; 1946,; 1949-1968; 7 folders (Box 27)
  - Articles by Knowles, 1969-1981; 13 folders (Box 28)
  - Articles by Knowles, 1982-1983; undated; 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Articles on communication by Everett M. Rogers, 1970's (Box 29)
  - Assessing and reporting training needs and progress, 1956 (Box 29)
  - Assessment papers (Box 29)
  - Association of Voluntary Action Scholars, 1976; 1977,; 1978; AVAS newsletter - vol. 4, no. 1; vol. 5, no. 1, 4; vol. 6, no. 1, 3 (Box 29)
  - Atlanta University School of Nursing, Curriculum and concept of autonomous social worker, 1972-1974 (Box 29)
  - Attempt to document research and training in adult education, by J.H. Knoll, 1972 (Box 29)
  - Auerbach Publications, 1981-1982 (Box 29)
  - Back to school: college guide for adults (book outline), by William C. Haponski and Charles E. McCabe, 1981 (Box 29)
  - Belchertown State School proposal, by Professor Karl J. Larson, 1967 (Box 29)
  - Bibliography on adult education, 1960 (Box 29)
  - Bibliography: reform and innovation in graduate education, by Malcolm S. Knowles, 1978 (Box 29)
  - Birth of an idea: women's continuing education: account of its genesis, by Elizabeth L. Cless, 1975 (Box 29)
  - Boston University
    - Bostonia, 1964 (Box 29)
    - Graduate Program in Adult and Higher Education, Adult education collection master bibliography, 1967-1978 (Box 29)
    - School of Education
      - Alumni news, vol. 4, no. 14, 1969 (Box 29)
      - Community newsletter, vol. 1, no. 4, 1973-1974 (Box 29)
      - Department of System Development and Adaptation Doctoral student handbook, 1973 (Box 30)
    - WGBH Leadership Training Project
      - Final report, 1962 (Box 30)
      - Dynamics of leadership viewer study guides, 1961; 1963 (Box 30)
  - Brandon Sun, "Adult education: new technique required, says professor," by Wayne Boyce, circa 1978 (Box 30)
  - Buffalo studies, vol. 2, no. 1, 1966 (Box 30)
  - Canadian journal of university continuing education, vol. 4, no. 1, 2, 1977-1978 (Box 30)
  - Career and educational counseling needs of adults: overview of the relevant literature, by Betty E. Knox, 1977 (Box 30)
  - Career and vocational counseling pamphlets and articles (Box 30)
  - Career education: Handbook for implementation, 1972 (Box 30)
  - Carnegie quarterly, vol. 17, no. 4, Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1969 (Box 30)
  - CEGOS
    - Club animateur
      - Quelques indications concernant l'utilisation des "contrats de formation" (learning contracts) dans la formation basée sur l'expérience, by Malcolm S. Knowles, circa 1979 (Box 30)
      - L’évolution des méthodes pédagogiques dans la formation des adultes (evolution of teaching methods in adult training), 1979 (Box 30)
    - Les documents de l'association CEGOS
      - Les différents types de pédagogie: leur application à la formation des adultes dans l'enterprise, by Henri Fraisse, 1979 (Box 30)
      - Une approche nouvelle de la formation des vendeurs, by Marc Corcos, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Center for a Voluntary Society proposal, 1972 (Box 30)
  - Central YMCA Community College, 1975; press release (Box 30)
  - Chapter selections from untitled book about values, by Don Ehet, 1982 (Box 30)
  - Chicago Public Schools Americanization and Adult Education Division, Adult education news - vol. 2, no. 1, 1948-1949 (Box 30)
  - Citizen participation and voluntary action abstracts, vol. 1 no. 1; vol. 2, no. 1; vol. 3, no. 1, 2; vol. 4, no. 1-3; vol. 5, no. 2-3 (Box 30)
  - Citizen Participation North Carolina Office Journal, 1975; 1976; vol. 1, no. 6, 7; vol. 2, no. 2
  - Cleveland State University College of Education, Department of Educational Specialists, Post-secondary education, 1978-1979
  - Cognitive style, learning style, and transfer skill acquisition, by Patricia Kirby, 1979 (Box 30)
  - College Board Research Advisory Panel on Lifelong Learning of the Future Directions for a Learning Society Project, papers on needed research and derivation activity (Box 30)
  - Colombia and higher education, undated (Box 30)
  - Columbia University Teachers College, Final report on Ed.D. and Ph.D. in adult and continuing education, by New York State Department of Education - Office of the Doctoral Project - Rating Committee, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Commission of Professors of Adult Education (CPAE)
    - Careers in adult and continuing education, 1968 (Box 30)
    - Newsletter, 1975; 1977-1980 (Box 31)
    - Progress report, 1967 (Box 31)
    - Skill bank report, 1969 (Box 31)
    - What's new, 1972-1973 (Box 31)
  - Communication Research Center, 1967; CRC newsletter, vol. 6, no. 1 (Box 31)
  - Community Treatment Project
    - After five years, undated (Box 31)
    - Evaluation of community treatment for delinquents, progress reports, 1966-1968; 3 folders (Box 31)
    - Overview of matching, by Ted Palmer, 1968 (Box 31)
    - Report series, 1967; 1969; no. 1; no. 1-3, 5 (Box 31)
  - Comparison of the effectiveness of the actuarial total and subpart scores of the gessel copy form test as predictors of school success, by Alexander J. Popovics, 1972 (Box 31)
  - Competency model revisions (Box 31)
  - Continuing education: bridging the information gap, 1975 (Box 31)
  - Continuing education: evolving form of adult education, undated (Box 32)
  - Continuing education for business, by Dr. Max G. Cooley, 1979 (Box 32)
  - Continuing education in Massachusetts: state programs for the '70s, by Melvin R. Levin and Joseph S. Slavet, 1970 (Box 32)
  - Continuing education in New Zealand, 1974; 1976; vol. 6, no. 2; vol. 8, no. 1 (Box 32)
  - Continuing education pamphlet and report, 1976-1978 (Box 32)
  - Continuing Library Education Network and Exchange, 1975-1976; vol. 1, no. 1-4 (Box 32)
  - Continuing medical education in your future, by Richard M. Caplan, M.D., 1971 (Box 32)
  - Continuous and integrated education of the adult as observed in industrial education programs, by R. Rowray, undated (Box 32)
  - Contributors to a discipline of adult education: review and analysis of the publications of Coolie Verner, by Gary Dickinson, 1979 (Box 32)
  - Cooperative Extension Service, Montana State University, Bozeman, Reservation agent, vol. 2, no. 9, 1971 (Box 32)
  - Coppin State College Courier, vol. 6, no. 8, 1974 (Box 32)
  - Corporation for Public Broadcasting - Adult Learning Program Service, 1972; papers and report on ALPS One (Box 32)
  - Cost and output of graduate social work education: exploratory study, 1970 (Box 32)
  - Council of Graduate Schools in the United States Requirements for the Ph.D., 1979 (Box 32)
  - Council on Social Work Education
    - Division on Standards and Accreditation, Undergraduate social work programs guide for site visits, 1971 (Box 32)
    - Exchange, no. 1, 1970 (Box 32)
  - Counseling papers and reports (Box 32)
  - Criteria in learning research, by King M. Wientge and Philip H. DuBois, 1966 (Box 32)
  - CRM/McGraw-Hill Films. On the job coaching, 1977-1979 (Box 33)
  - Cumulative index of ERIC resources in counseling and personnel services 1967-1976, by Garry R. Walz, Libby Benjamin and Marc E. Ruby, 1977 (Box 33)
  - Current action principles and concepts from research and theory in adult learning and development, by Robert A. Fox (Box 33)
  - Current research needs related to systematic learning by adults, by Alan B. Knox, 1977 (Box 33)
  - Cutting edge group, by Anne Hillman, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Data Education, Inc. proposal, undated (Box 33)
  - Degree research in adult education in Canada: 1968-March 1969, by James A. Draper, John A. Niemi and Claude Touchette (Box 33)
  - Delta Kappa Gamma Bulletin, vol. 45, no. 3, 1979 (Box 33)
  - Design and implementation of adult education experiences: conversation with Malcolm Knowles, by Roger Boshier, circa 1977 (Box 33)
  - Developing a market strategy model for continuing education programs, Chapter 2 - Developing the model from the literature, by Andrew M. Brown, 1984 (Box 33)
  - Development and improvement of adult educational programs, by Cyril O. Houle, undated (Box 33)
  - Development of adult education in Japan, 1966 (Box 33)
  - Diagnostic guides, undated (Box 33)
  - Differences between teaching adults and pre-adults: some propositions and findings, by Harold W. Beder and Gordon G. Darkenwald, undated (Box 33)
  - Directions in healthcare education & training, vol. 7, no. 3, 1982 (Box 33)
  - Directory of consultants for planning adult learning systems, facilities and environments 1973-1974, by Adult Education Association of the U.S.A. (Box 33)
  - Directory of information resources in the United States: social sciences, by National Referral Center for Science and Technology, 1965 (Box 33)
  - Directory of residential continuing education centers in the United States and Canada, 1963-1964; 1965 (Box 34)
  - Directory of resources for the education of adults 1978-1979, by J. Nevin Robbins, Darlene L. Sork with Ted Brunell and Sheila Rosen (Box 34)
  - Distinguished adult educators explore issues/trends/strategies in adult/continuing education, ed. by S. Gregory Bowes, 1978 (Box 34)
  - DuPont Company Clinical Systems Division, undated; learning systems papers and pamphlets (Box 34)
  - Eduard Lindeman and the idea of lifelong learning in America (book proposal), by David W. Stewart, circa 1983 (Box 34)
  - Educating the adult educator
    - Part 1: Concepts of the curriculum, by Burton W. Kreitlow, 1965 (Box 34)
    - Part 2: Taxonomy of needed research, by Burton W. Kreitlow, 1968 (Box 34)
  - Education and the development of human technology, by Kenneth L. Neff, 1962 (Box 34)
  - Education course outlines, 1976-1978 (Box 34)
  - Education material catalogs, undated (Box 34)
  - Education of adults in U.S.S.R., by Ferdinand Herz, 1975 (Box 34)
  - Educational ethos of the midwestern high school, by Herbert A. Thelen, 1974 (Box 34)
  - Educational orientation, assessment and rating scales, 1970's (Box 34)
  - Educational researcher, vol. 8, no. 3, 1979 (Box 34)
  - Educational Resources Information Center (ERIC)
    - Proposal, 1972 (Box 34)
    - Clearinghouse on Adult, Career, and Vocational Education, Information series no. 172, 173, 1979 (Box 34)
    - Counseling and Personnel Services, Searchlight: relevant resources in high interest areas, no. 8, 11, 12, 22C, 24, 33, 1966-1977 (Box 34)
  - Effect of extension service's youth nutrition lesson series on behavioral change in EFNEP youth utilizing different educational environments and teachers (executive summary), by Estelle E. White, Edgar J. Boone and Robert J. Monroe, 1976 (Box 34)
  - Emergent practices in the continuing education of school administrators, by Frank W. Lutz and Reynolds Ferrante, 1972 (Box 34)
  - Emerging education policy issues in law: public-private competition in higher education, by Stuart A. Sandow, 1971 (Box 34)
  - Enhancing the application of adult learning principles to continuing education of health professionals, 1978 (Box 34)
  - Enhancing your proficiencies in the design and facilitation of adult literacy education, by George Aker, Ruth Spaulding, Rosemary Adams, and B.B. White, 1984 (Box 35)
  - Enrollments in the '80s: factors, actors and impacts, by J. Victor Baldridge, Frank R. Kemerer and Kenneth C. Green, 1982 (Box 35)
  - Entrepreneurship and management in the years ahead, by David C. McClelland, 1977 (Box 35)
  - ERIC
    - Clearinghouse on Adult Education, Information analysis series advertisement, circa 1977 (Box 35)
    - Search Service specification and query listing, 1972 (Box 35)